Pradnya Purandare

Pune, Maharashtra, India. Zip code-411011 Mobile No. +918999143950

E-mail Id: pradnyac@yahoo.com

OBJECTIVE:

To Pursue carrier in the field of finance, acquire new skills, utilize current skills and work closely with a team of professionals.

SUMMARY PROFILE:

10+ years' experience in handling various Finance, Accounts & Taxation related activities Possess strong analytical and problem-solving skills, with the ability to make well thought-out decisions.

Managed complex tasks efficiently and effectively for which got appreciation from Sr. management.

Highly trustworthy, discreet and ethical.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION:

Successfully completed accounting technician course from Institute of Chartered Accountants of India (C.A. Intermediate).

Master degree in Accounting from Pune University with second class.

Bachelor degree in accounting from Pune University with first class.

RELATED PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Vodafone India Services Pvt. Ltd.: (1st December 22 to till date)

- Month end closing
- Accrual and reallocation journals
- Balance sheet reconciliations
- Variance Analysis
- Audit queries

Johnson Controls: (1st March 19 to till April 22)

Deputy Manager:

- Transition of process from Europe to India as a part of project and provisioning team.
- Revenue recognition as per ASC 606-IFRS/ US GAAP
- Reallocations of costs and revenues.
- Monthly closing- Accruals, warranty provisions, matching costs/ revenues
- Closing projects/ warranty projects on completion.
- Monitoring project wise work in progress amounts.
- Balance sheet reconciliations.
- Calculation of warranty provision as per policy.
- Calculation of inventory provision as per policy.
- Preparation of statistical data of backlog, secured volume and margins.
- Impart training to new members of team.

- Sox compliances.
- Handling audit
- HFM error removal.
- Conduct training on various policies of organization.

Maersk GSC India Pvt. Ltd. (May 18 to Feb 19) Senior Analyst- ATR:

- Working on joint ventures and fixed cost controlling.
- Studying vessel sharing agreements carefully.
- Monitoring data of vessels and voyages, loading of partner on the vessels
- calculation of slot cost considering cost elements and as per terms and conditions of vessel sharing agreements and invoicing partner on structural basis. Invoicing excess loading as per terms of contracts. Updating partners about changes in cost elements. Recovering allied costs incurred, from the partners as per terms of contract.
- Preparing outstanding report and aging analysis weekly. Sending reminders to partners
 and recovering overdue amounts. Clearing receivables against funds received from the
 partners.
- Resolving disputes received from partners. Verifying invoices received from partners.
- Preparing accrual data every month end. Recognizing revenue as per IFRS on the basis of performance obligation. Accruing cost at the end of the month as per terms of contracts for the invoices not received. Post accruals in SAP.
- Preparing month-end closing reports to meet SLAs. Preparing service-wise analysis of
 income and expense. Making YTD adjustments. Comparing actuals with rolling
 forecasts. Analyzing reasons for deviation between rolling forecasts and actuals.
 Preparing deviation report for current month vs previous month, current year vs previous
 year analyzing reasons for deviations.
- GL reconciliation.
- Conducting calls with stakeholders to explain month end reports and taking sign off.

Tulips Ambbience Pvt. Ltd. (Sep 2017 to April 2018) Finance Manager:

- Handling team, supervising correct and timely maintenance of books of accounts in SAP.
- Monthly closing entries. GL scrutiny.
- MIS of four verticals and Consolidation thereof.
- Daily cash flow planning.
- Coordinating and planning with various departments, getting departmental budgets from them and consolidation thereof.
- Monitoring bank accounts and reconciliation thereof.
- Controlling petty cash expenses.
- PO finance, foreign inward remittances, utilization of limits & packing credit limits, due dates of installments of various loans, checking availability of funds, checking outstanding interest and installments. Submitting stock statements, Handling stock audits.
- Applications for new loans, meeting the requirement of banks.
- Intercompany balance reconciliation, Finalization, closing Entries, making provisions.
- Maintenance of fixed asset register, finalization of accounts, handle statutory auditors.

- Debtors Reconciliation.
- Statutory compliance: providing data for TDS returns, GST returns, Income tax returns, Roc filings, handling vat audit.

Williams Controls India Pvt. Ltd. (Curtiss-Wright) (Oct 2011 to April 2015) Sr. Executive Accounts & Finance:

- GL reconciliation, Accounts Receivables, Intercompany balance reconciliation, closing journal entries, Fixed Asset accounting, Maintenance of books of accounts as per US GAAP and as per Indian Accounting Standards.
- Updation of standard costing in ERP system.
- Variance analysis.
- MIS, Monthly closing of accounts.
- TDS return, Providing data to sales tax consultant, Excise consultants. Reconciliation of accounts with various excise and vat registers.
- Providing data for Secretarial work related to annual return, various board resolution.
- Maintenance of fixed asset register, finalization of accounts, handle statutory auditors.
- Salary Processing.

Trinity India Ltd. (Jan 2010 to Sep 2011):

Officer Accounts:

- Projected cash flow, daily actual cash flow and bank position.
- Submission of monthly stock statements to bank. Preparation of FFRs.
- Monthly balance sheet and profitability- Projected and actual.
- Keeping track of PO finance, foreign inward remittances, utilization of FBD limits & packing credit limits, due dates of installments of various loans, checking availability of funds, checking outstanding interest and installments. Maintaining record of LC utilization limit.
- Applications for new loans, meeting the requirement of banks.
- Bank Reconciliation-daily /monthly. -CC, PO finance, FDs,CA, Term loans.
- Preparation of monthly sales summary and matching with excise records.
- Reconciliation of inter unit sale-purchase.
- Accounts receivables. Debtors aging.
- Preparation of Bill of exchange, hundies. Bank correspondence for foreign bill discounting, packing credit etc.
- Keeping track of Deposits from directors, shareholders and others and interest thereon.
- Finalization, closing Entries, making accruals and provisions.

Special Assignment: Handled Due Diligence Audit for sale of company.

Venkateshwara Hatcheries Pvt. Ltd. (Associate of Venky India Ltd.) Officer Accounts (May 2008 to August 2009)

 MIS Reporting: monthly Operating profit statements of various divisions and consolidation thereof, Preparation of Budgets, co-coordinating with various departments for collection of information related to budget, Variance Analysis, Stock Valuation, Product costing.

- cash flow statements.
- Aging of Accounts Receivables and Payable s.
- Quarterly Information Statements giving estimates, actual performance and actual Vs. estimated position and submitting them to various banks on due dates. Submission of stock statements to banks on due dates.
- Bank reconciliation statements.
- Forecasting of working capital needs.
- Taxation: Advance income tax, E-TDS returns, vat returns, service tax and FBT returns.
- Handling Vat audit.
- Intercompany Reconciliations, FAR, Accruals and provisions.
- Balance sheet and schedules.
- Adhering to compliance with various laws like Income tax Act, Companies Act and application of accounting standards.
- Handling tax audit as well as internal and statutory audit.

COMPUTER LITERACY:

Well conversant with ERP system-SAP, iscala, Aurora (JBA), Beacon ERP, Tally ERP 9, Word, Excel, PowerPoint, HFM reporting etc.

PERSONAL DETAILS:

Name : Pradnya Purandare-Chinchore.

DOB : 14-03-1981 Sex : Female Marital Status : Married

Professional References: Available on request.

(Pradnya Purandare.)